Karthik Vibuthi

Baltimore, MD | (667) 391 2842 | karthikvibuthi555@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio

Summary

Full time experienced in software engineering in full stack development, coding practices and hands on experience with data bricks, machine learning and AI practices. I am pursuing areas of software development with machine learning adoption.

Professional Experiences

Software Engineer

Oct 2024 – present

Ardent Privacy, Baltimore

- Software engineer in Angular framework on data privacy domain developed privacy tools like data subject requests, privacy automation with Ai/ML adoption, which improved development effort by 2 days.
- Implemented responsive design principles on large scale web applications and optimal data modeling principles on MongoDb.

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Aug 2024 – Dec 2024

University of Maryland Baltimore County UMBC, Baltimore

- Teaching Assistant for Big Data Processing class helped student in learning Data bricks, Spark, Hadoop, Mongo DB concepts and graded assignments with project guidance for more than 50 students.
- Helped professors in creating assignments, quizzes, paper writing, academic research and adapting and reviewing AI tools in the class work.

Software Engineer

Nov 2020 – Dec 2022

CGI, Chennai, India

- Software engineer in Full stack development on AngularJS and NodeJS, Quality Assurance with focus in Client delivery, DevOps Automation, Static Code testing and Infrastructure Management in AWS cloud.
- Automated pipelines for Feature testing, tool migration, and data movement reducing manual effort by 40 % accelerating adoption of new features and requirements which directly increased new clients and scan capacity.
- Promoted to software engineer in 1 year along with Young Achiever Award for my efforts in all areas.

Web developer Intern

May 2020 – Nov 2020

Propelsum, Hyderabad, India

- An emerging front-end developer working with a software consultancy firm to build their portfolio website utilizing Angular JS framework. Finished deployment of the website 2 weeks early to the release date.
- Quickly progressed from developer role to the build manager, taking responsibility for the repository and leading
 a team of four, providing continuous support, and incorporating three business transactions based on the evolving
 requirements.

Education

Master of Professional Studies: (Data Science – CGPA 3.97)

Jan 2023 - Present

University of Maryland at Baltimore County.

Skills: Data Analysis, Data Bricks, Machine Learning, Power BI, Python.

Bachelor in Electronics and Communication Engineering (CGPA -3.72)

Aug 2016 – June 2020

Sreenidhi Institute of Science and Technology.

Skills: Operating systems, Java, Communication Engineering, Networking, Micro controllers, and Micro Processors, VLSI.

Skills

Languages:

Bitbucket, Git, Confluence, Jira.

Python, Java Script, C, C++, HTML, CSS

Databases:

Cloud Services: AWS Cloud, AWS LightSail. MongoDB, Data Bricks, PostgreSQL

Automation/CI/CD Tools and Systems:

Routing and Switchin

Certifications: IBM Data engineering, CCNA (Cisco

Jenkins, PowerShell, Linux, Grafana, Ubuntu, Windows, Ro